# **Brandon Jason Valle Tamayo Software Backend Developer**

bjvtamayo78@gmail.com

# **Summary**

Brandon is a Software Developer specialized in Back-end development. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic projects.

He is well-versed in numerous programming languages including Ruby, Python, PHP OOP, and JavaScript. Also worked as a QA creating automated tests and has worked as a DevOps Engineer using Docker and Ansible for CI / CD and has project management experience with small groups.

Brandon is a complex problem solver, has self-motivation to learn, and enjoys working as a team member.

## **Technical Expertise**

- Ruby on Rails
- Python with Flask and Django
- Test Driven Development, Behavior Driven Development

# **Work Experience**

## **Ruby on Rails Engineer**

Agile Testing Fellow January 2023 - Present

#### **Job Description**

- Improved SEO website in 20%
- Identified ideas to improve system performance and impact availability

#### **Senior Ruby Software Developer**

Believe Solutions LLC (Bolivia) - Folionet LLC (USA) February 2022 – January 2023

- Covered 50% of test
- Enabled continuous integration at 100%
- Wrote well designed, testable, efficient code.
- Fixed 100% of bugs with external services
- Documented and demonstrated solutions by developing documentation, flowcharts, layouts, diagrams, charts, code comments and clear code
- Integrated banking at 90% with Modern Treasury.

Added 4 cron jobs to solve human tasks.

# Senior Python/Ruby Developer

Trending Technology Services GmbH (Berlin – Germany) Jun 2019 – Nov 2022

- Created an invoice system from scratch.
- Maintained product quality by carrying out reviews, performing continual tests, analyzing feedback, and managing software integration.
- Designed, coded, and supported software solutions that can easily be handled by the situation
- Created test suites to assess product functionality and performance
- Built extensive test coverage for all new features, which reduced the customer report bugs in 30%
- Implemented CI/CD with Ansible and Gitlab and reduces the human deployment process in 100%.
- I was the lead developer for more than 3 years.

#### **Senior Python Developer**

Muquo Games SL (Sevilla – Spain) Nov 2020 – Feb 2022

- Built a module in python which was made with TDD and covered 100%.
- Created 3 Automated Test with Selenium to run every day at the same time in GitLab.
- Increased performance in saving and return data from 27 seconds to 7, using recursive functions in PostgreSQL.
- I was the lead of the backend team.

#### **Consultant Software Developer**

bjvSoft.net (Santa Cruz – Bolivia) Jun 2019 – Present

#### **Job Description**

- Has mentored junior software developers on design patterns, development best practices and DevOps trade-offs
- Designed and guided to create 2 SaaS systems
- Liaised with Product Managers to identify minimum viable product requirements and clearly defined feature sets into well-scoped user stories for individual team members.

#### **Software Developer**

Ticketeg S.R.L. (Santa Cruz - Bolivia) Jul 2016 - June 2019

- Collaborated an accounting system, warehouse using Ruby and Rails.
- Developed application prototypes and participated in client meetings
- Worked with a team of IT professionals to develop proprietary, secure, and webaccessible database

#### Main skills

- Ruby
- Ruby on Rails
- Python
- Django
- Flask
- PHP
- JavaScript
- Docker
- Ansible
- PostgreSQL
- MySQL
- AWS: EC2, Route53, S3, SES.

## **Education**

**Gabriel Rene Moreno Autonomous University** 

Computer Science 2011 - 2018

# **Complementary experience**

Agile Testing Days 2019 Conference - Potsdam Germany Speaker

Agile Testing Days 2022 Conference - Chicago USA Speaker

# Languages

Spanish: Native English: Advance